<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rss version='2.0'><channel><title>thermalspan</title><link>thermalspan.github.io/</link><description>website of Russell Bentley</description><item><title>First Post</title><link>thermalspan.github.io/posts/post-1.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;This is our first Post!&lt;/h1&gt;
</description><guid>thermalspan.github.io/posts/post-1.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 21:00:30 -0500</pubDate></item><item><title>Firstsdfsdf</title><link>thermalspan.github.io/posts/post-3.html</link><description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;this-is-an-article&quot;&gt;This is an article!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is some text!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a list item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is another list item!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First we will examine what regular expressions are. Then we will show some uses for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some examples to consider would be the following. * checking if something is in a set! * Not emails, but maybe last names in spacing? * Or addresses? * Or something on an alphabet that doesn&apos;t use characters? so we can stress the generality of the pure definition later? Perhaps something like trains? * Lol we could have half life 2 inspired interlude with train types! Finite sets of cars! Civilian and combine! But also the WAY THINGS WORK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we will go into more formal detail about what they are. First thing would regular languages. Regular expressions are then presented as a language whose sentences are valid regular anguages. Sentences in the instructions that make regular exressions.&lt;br /&gt;
* A formal defintions in terms of an alphabet and the basic operations * Some of the usual &lt;span class=&quot;math inline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;b&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;c&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&quot;math inline&quot;&gt;0, 1&lt;/span&gt; examples, but make them connect to other things, like Huffman codes&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnoteRef&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there we will demonstrate and fully explore the &amp;quot;high level&amp;quot; features that we want. Things like character classes. These are characters that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Huffman codes have a special ordering. How do we want to reference them? Would be sweet to have links to other cool articles and then link them, but also have a page of linked pages, could have an auto generated pages thing goin on, with a sweet expanding tree like interface. That would be sooooo dope.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><guid>thermalspan.github.io/posts/post-3.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 21:00:30 -0500</pubDate></item><item><title>Regular Expressions</title><link>thermalspan.github.io/posts/regular_expressions.html</link><description>extends: default.liquid</description><guid>thermalspan.github.io/posts/regular_expressions.html</guid></item><item><title>Website Setup</title><link>thermalspan.github.io/posts/website_setup.html</link><description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;website-setup&quot;&gt;Website Setup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post documents how my website is setup. Since I deploy it via github pages, that really ammounts to how it is built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premise is that I have several component projects that all dump their build artifacts into a common root directory. I then run the a templater on that directory to produce the final website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need the following special tools in your &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cobalt&quot;&gt;Cobalt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cobalt-org/cobalt.rs&quot;&gt;cobalt.rs&lt;/a&gt; is a static site generator. I am currently using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Cobalt 0.7.2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to install cobalt is probably:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cargo install cobalt-bin&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pandoc&quot;&gt;pandoc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pandoc.org&quot;&gt;pandoc&lt;/a&gt; is best described on their homepage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to convert files from one markup format into another, pandoc is your swiss-army knife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The version of pandoc I am using is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pandoc 1.19.2.1
Compiled with pandoc-types 1.17.0.5, texmath 0.9, skylighting 0.1.1.4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed pandoc using brew:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install pandoc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;blockpass&quot;&gt;blockpass&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ThermalSpan/blockpass&quot;&gt;blockpass&lt;/a&gt; is a small utility I wrote. Top of tree should be fine for now. You can install by downloading and building it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/ThermalSpan/blockpass.git
cd blockpass
cargo install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dependences&quot;&gt;Dependences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are are the projects that contribute content to the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;KaTeX&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Khan/KaTeX&quot;&gt;blockpass&lt;/a&gt; is a javascript library for math rendering. From Khan Academy! I am currently using the following tag:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;v0.7.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pandoc supports KaTeX in html, so that&apos;s how I use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pandoc-posts&quot;&gt;pandoc-posts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ThermalSpan/pandoc-posts&quot;&gt;pandoc-posts&lt;/a&gt; is the repository where most of the posts live. Top of tree on the master branch should be sufficient. Drafts live in other branches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;thermalspan.github.io-source&quot;&gt;thermalspan.github.io-source&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ThermalSpan/thermalspan.github.io-source&quot;&gt;thermalspan.github.io-source&lt;/a&gt; is kitchen sink for this website. All the templates, misc pages, and such live here. And for now the &amp;quot;build system&amp;quot; does too, but I&apos;d like to rip that out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pandoc posts project is really important, and is where most of the content lives. I would like to keep it as a seperate repisotory since it represents a good content divide. It also allows the issue tracker to be used soley for content related issues. I can also the branches to cleany mark drafts and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My short term goals are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have three articles that aren&apos;t totally embarrassing in the pandoc-posts project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a better build script / or find an off the shelf solution that meets my needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixup the connect page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My medium term goals are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Template the posts to include download link to pdf version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include some projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps host some documentation, though this is pending having a project that&apos;s worth documenting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To go with above, allow build script to build and include documentation in a clean way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My long term goals are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seperate build system / templater from the webpage source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include fancier front page options for sorting through options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include a source option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include at least one webGL / javascript interactive project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some nifty ideas that might be worth implementing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That progress bar that quantamagazine has on their articles is awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Post ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk about cargo cache commands and how you use them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk about nvim setup, or at least one useful trick for configuring SpaceVim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create Context Free Grammer cheatsheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walk through a cool math problem to show off all that awesome KaTeX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce some notation and explain its tradeoffs. Like bra-ket, or Einstein summation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take some notes on the many papers you think you&apos;ve read, maybe a prolog implementation paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To maintain a list of other notable places on the web. Like other personal websites and such. Though, this might be better as a pure website for interactive purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><guid>thermalspan.github.io/posts/website_setup.html</guid></item></channel></rss>